You must not do this. Your Royal Highness, no!
‪不可以这么做啊 邸下！
Oh, no. Your Royal Highness…
‪天啊 邸下！
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
Gosh…
‪唉唷
Why did you do it?
‪你为何要那么做？
Why did you do such a thing?
‪你为何闯下那种祸？
I put my faith in you.
‪寡人如此信任你
Yet, you disappointed me.
‪你却让寡人大失所望
You did the right thing.
‪您做得很好
Your Royal Highness,
‪邸下确实
you did the right thing.
‪做得很好
You are a brave, bold man who can beat up the Chief Eunuch.
‪您这个男子汉都有胆量打飞太监了
I'm sure you can handle this much.
‪怎么会这么怕痛？
That's enough.
‪这样就可以了
Let me just treat your hand.
‪让臣帮您把手包扎好
This might not be the right time to bring this up,
‪虽然不晓得现在提这个是否适宜
but I know that you saw me at the guesthouse.
‪但臣知道您在太平馆看到我了
I know I shouldn't have been there, so I'm sorry if that disappointed you.
‪我知道那不是适合出席的场合 ‪若让您失望 我很抱歉
But I can promise you that
‪不过那天
I didn't do anything to disgrace myself.
‪我绝对没做出让自己羞愧的事
So in case you misread the situation--
‪因此若您因为那件事而误会…
I never did.
‪我没有误会
I know that
‪因为我知道
you are not the type of person who would do such a thing.
‪郑司书不是那种趋炎附势的人
Then…
‪那您为何
why were you so distant toward me during the banquet?
‪在宴会时对我如此冷淡？
Well…
‪那是…
I didn't want you to be in a tight spot because of me.
‪我不希望你因为我陷入为难的处境
That's why.
‪所以才会那样
I feel the same way.
‪我也是同样的想法
So if you know how I feel,
‪既然您知道我的心意
please don't be distant toward me anymore.
‪就别再对我如此冷淡了
There. It's all done.
‪好 都包扎好了
EPISODE 8
‪第 8 集
I'm really fine, Your Royal Highness.
‪小的真的不要紧
Your hand is hurt too.
‪您的手上还有伤啊
I told you not to move.
‪都叫你坐好了
How beautiful.
‪真美
Your hair looks beautiful
‪即便是短发
even when it's short.
‪也真的很美
I have a chance to get my hair done by you thanks to the Chief Eunuch.
‪多亏太监 还让小的有幸让邸下梳发
This is truly a blessing.
‪这真是莫大的福气啊
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
The Chief Eunuch's subordinate is here.
‪太监派他的手下过来
He invited you, the Vice Minister of Rites,
‪要邀请您和礼部侍郎及郑司书
and Royal Tutor Jung for a drink.
‪一起饮酒同酌
He did?
‪太监吗？
Yes. Should I tell them to station some royal guards?
‪是的 要暗中部署翊卫司吗？
That's all right. I can't afford to use a cheap trick like that.
‪不用了 不能再因那种伎俩
There can't be any more problems.
‪衍生出任何问题了
I will get going first.
‪我先去赴约
Go and bring Royal Tutor Jung to the guesthouse.
‪你带郑司书随后赶至太平馆
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
‪是 邸下
It seems the Vice Minister of Rites hasn't arrived yet.
‪为何不见礼部侍郎？
Men can resolve this kind of matter over drinks.
‪男人之间能借着酒席 ‪坦诚以对 化解间隙
There is no point in bothering other people.
‪可不能给周围的人带来麻烦啊
Please sit.
‪请坐
As a peace offering,
‪作为和解
I thought I could show you something interesting.
‪我想让您看个有趣的东西
So I asked you to come.
‪才会邀您前来
What do you say?
‪您意下如何？
Come on out.
‪出来吧
From what I hear,
‪据我所知
your bodyguard is the best swordsman in Joseon.
‪您的护卫是朝鲜第一剑
Who do you think will win?
‪他们俩相互较量 您觉得谁会胜出？
That doesn't interest me.
‪我并不是很想知道
If this is why you asked to see me, you can count me out.
‪若是因为这种事找我过来 ‪那我没兴致奉陪
I will head back now.
‪告辞
Let's go back.
‪回宫吧
Stop it! What do you think you're doing?
‪快住手！你好大的胆子！
My guard is the best swordsman in Ming.
‪这个明国第一剑
But he wasn't with me when I was getting beaten to a pulp.
‪在他主子血流满面时刚好不在岗位上
So I thought he deserved a chance to show me he's worth his salary.
‪因此我必须给他一个机会表现 ‪让他无愧于他的俸禄
Stop this immediately!
‪立刻给我住手！
Why? You were having fun when you were beating me up.
‪怎么了？您对我拳头相向时 ‪打得那么起劲
But you don't want to see your man getting beaten up?
‪却不愿见到自己的手下挨打吗？
I told you to stop!
‪我不是要你住手吗？
Do you think you'll be able
‪你认为在朝鲜土地上
to leave Joseon unscathed if you leave a scratch on me?
‪伤了我之后还能全身而退吗？
Are you all right?
‪你还好吗？
If you put a finger on the Crown Prince…
‪你若敢伤及世子邸下分毫
I will…
‪你就…
kill you.
‪死定了
With my own hands.
‪死在我手上
Royal Tutor Jung.
‪郑司书
Are you all right, Your Royal Highness?
‪您没事吧？邸下
Your Royal Highness!
‪邸下！
Your Royal Highness. Goodness.
‪邸下！唉唷
-Oh, no. -What is going on here?
‪-你醒醒啊 ‪-这到底是怎么回事？
-Bring a physician. -Yes, my lord!
‪-快找医员过来！ ‪-是
Oh, no. Are you all right?
‪你醒醒啊 你还好吗？
This is no fun.
‪还真无趣
How dare you pull out your sword in front of His Royal Highness?
‪你怎么敢在邸下面前拔刀？
How dare you do this?
‪你竟敢做出这种事？
It wasn't my intention, but the fight seems to have gotten heated.
‪战斗出乎意料的激烈
If you are disgruntled, take it up with me.
‪若有不满就直接告诉我
Leave the innocent alone.
‪不要伤及无辜的人！
How could I dare to do so?
‪我岂敢对邸下直言不讳？
Well, don't you keep them around,
‪反正雇用下人
so they can take your place in punishment
‪就是要让他们代受皮肉之痛
and do your dirty work for you?
‪或者为那些见不得人的事善后
Why are you doing this?
‪你为何要这么做？
-What is it that you want? -What do I want?
‪-你到底想要什么？ ‪-我想要什么？
Right. There is one thing I want from Joseon.
‪对了 我来朝鲜只有一个期望
People like you who were born with a silver spoon
‪将您这种明明贵为金枝玉叶
are hypocrites who pretend to care for the people.
‪却故作替百姓着想的可恶之徒
And I want to destroy people like you.
‪全数踩在脚底下 就是我的期望
I guess we will have to drink next time, Your Royal Highness.
‪那就下次再一起同酌了 邸下
This way.
‪这边
Put him down here.
‪让他躺下
Do you think he'll wake up?
‪他醒得过来吗？
Fortunately, he stopped bleeding.
‪庆幸的是 血已经止住了
But the cut is too deep. We'll have to observe him for a while.
‪但伤口很深 可能要再观察一下
What on earth happened?
‪这到底是怎么回事啊？
My lord. We have an urgent message from the guesthouse.
‪大监 太平馆紧急捎来口信
The Crown Prince's bodyguard was badly hurt by the Chief Eunuch's guard.
‪世子邸下的护卫武士 ‪被太监的武士所重伤
How is the Crown Prince?
‪邸下平安无事吗？
Yes. He returned to his quarters just now.
‪是 邸下刚回到东宫殿
Is the Chief Eunuch at the guesthouse?
‪太监目前在太平馆里吗？
What did you say?
‪你说什么？
How dare you talk about her here?
‪你竟敢在这里提起她？
Please hear me out. I just wanted to say there's no reason to shed blood here.
‪我只是说不要在这里见血
For that poor girl's sake.
‪就算是为了那个可怜的孩子
You cannot do this to me!
‪你也不该这样对我！
What did you say?
‪-你说什么？ ‪-天啊
I will visit you tomorrow night.
‪我明晚会去找你
So wait quietly.
‪你回去安分地等着
Yes, my lord.
‪是 小的遵命
Goodness.
‪唉唷
What brings you here this late at night?
‪者隐君 你这个时间来访有何贵干？
I heard that your guard badly hurt the Crown Prince's bodyguard.
‪听说邸下的护卫武士 ‪被你的武士所重伤
Not only did you cut off the hair of a court lady from his quarters,
‪你不但割断东宫殿尚宫的发髻
but you also hurt his guard.
‪现在连他的武士也不放过
I would like to know why.
‪我想了解个中缘由
Why are you making such a fuss over your subordinates?
‪你又何必为了下人的事大惊小怪呢？
Right. I heard a very interesting story.
‪对了
Someone the Emperor trusts very dearly
‪某个深受皇帝信赖的人
has been stealing offerings to the Emperor.
‪暗中拦截进贡至皇室的物品
I heard this person in question is also stealing the Emperor's private assets.
‪可能连皇帝的内帑金也占为己有
Don't you want to know who that person is?
‪你难道不好奇那是何人所为吗？
Are you trying to threaten me
‪你是打算用那种荒诞无稽的传闻
with that groundless rumor?
‪来威胁我吗？
I hear that the Emperor has high expectations for you.
‪皇帝对你抱有很高的期望吧？
The higher they are, the harder they will fall.
‪期待越高 就越容易失望
Unless you want there to be a big scandal,
‪若你不想闹大此事
I advise you to behave for the remainder of your trip here.
‪那我奉劝你安分地完成此趟出使
How ridiculous.
‪真是可笑
I don't see why you would want to do this to me.
‪你似乎没理由这样警告我啊
I'm afraid you're mistaken.
‪你可能不太清楚
I have many reasons why I must.
‪可是有诸多理由促使我这么做
"It is why traitor Kang Hwa-gil will hereby be executed by beheading."
‪“因此大逆罪人姜澕佶 ‪处斩首之刑”
Don't move. Your wound is severe.
‪你不要起身 你的伤势很严重
I'm sorry, Your Royal Highness.
‪臣惶恐
I have failed my duty to protect you.
‪我未能尽到保护邸下的本分
Do not say that.
‪别这么说
I have failed to protect you too.
‪我也同样保护不了你
What is it that infuriated and saddened you this much?
‪是什么让你那么气愤又哀伤
To the point that you were suffering even in your dream.
‪害你连在梦中都如此痛苦？
You still need to recover.
‪你的身体尚未康复
You shouldn't move. Just rest up here.
‪不要起身 好好休息吧
Hyun.
‪王兄
Is your bodyguard all right?
‪你的护卫武士还好吗？
Yes. He passed a critical moment.
‪是 他已度过危险关头
The people at my quarters are suffering because of me.
‪东宫殿的人似乎时常因为我而受罪
And I feel burdened by that.
‪我的心里很不好受
You're not to blame here. The Chief Eunuch is at fault.
‪那怎么能怪你呢？ ‪应该归咎于太监才对
He's dangerous.
‪他是个危险人物
So if there is a problem with him, you should tell me right away.
‪因此往后若出了什么事 ‪就马上告诉我
If you're hurt, I'm hurt too.
‪你难受的话 我也会跟着难受
So don't feel burdened.
‪所以不要独自承担
You have me, Your Royal Highness.
‪你的身边还有我啊
Thank you, Hyun.
‪谢谢你 王兄
You saw someone suspicious in the Chief Eunuch's chambers?
‪您在太监的住所看到可疑之人？
That brings me to my next point. I need your help.
‪所以我需要你的帮忙
Double our tribute?
‪贡品增为两倍？
Did the Chief Eunuch demand this too?
‪这也是太监的要求吗？
-Let me talk with him. -There is no need.
‪-孩儿去找他谈 ‪-不需要
I'll take care of this.
‪这件事寡人自会处理
You are not to get involved any further. You can leave now.
‪所以你别再插手 退下吧
I can't do that.
‪恕孩儿难以从命
I will resolve this problem between the Chief Eunuch and me.
‪我跟太监的问题由我来解决
Please put your faith in me one more time.
‪请您再相信孩儿一次
Please…
‪请给我
give me a chance, Father.
‪一个机会 父王
Why does the Chief Eunuch keep causing trouble?
‪太监那个人为何不断惹是生非？
He ought to help us since he's from Joseon.
‪他同是朝鲜人 理应维护同胞才是
Sometimes, your own people can be even worse.
‪总之有时候自家人反而更可怕
What do I want?
‪我想要什么？
People like you who were born with a silver spoon
‪将您这种明明贵为金枝玉叶
are hypocrites who pretend to care for the people.
‪却故作替百姓着想的可恶之徒
And I want to destroy people like you.
‪全数踩在脚底下 就是我的期望
Royal Tutor Jung is close to the Vice Minister of Rites, right?
‪郑司书和礼部侍郎关系很亲近对吧？
Yes. That's what I've heard.
‪是的 据传是如此
I must look into the Chief Eunuch.
‪得着手调查太监才行
Goodness.
‪唉唷
Tail the Chief Eunuch tonight,
‪今晚尾随太监的话
and you'll be able to find out who that man is.
‪就能得知他的真实身份
Royal Tutor Jung wasn't at the royal institute.
‪郑司书居然不在侍讲院里
What business does he have at the guesthouse?
‪他有什么事得跑太平馆一趟啊？
Goodness. Your Royal Highness, over there.
‪唉唷 邸下 那边
-You stay here. -What?
‪-你在这等着 ‪-什么？
Wait. Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
I'll go alone from this point on. You can wait here.
‪从这里开始我一个人走 你在这等着
Yes, my lord.
‪是
Kill him!
‪砍死他
-How did you… -Be careful.
‪-您怎么会来这？ ‪-小心一点
Goodness.
‪唉唷 我的天啊
If you ever use her to blackmail me again,
‪下次你再拿她来威胁我的话
I will cut off your head.
‪你的项上人头就会不保
Of course. Don't worry. You will never see me again.
‪那当然 你大可放心 ‪我不会再来找你了
We've been followed. You must get out of here now.
‪似乎有人尾随我们 ‪你得尽快离开这里
What?
‪什么？
Are you all right?
‪您没事吧？
Stop!
‪住手！
This way!
‪往这边
Arrest everyone who has caused a disturbance here!
‪把在此闹事的人全都抓起来！
-Yes, my lord!
‪-是
-Catch them! Stop them! -Get them!
‪-站住！给我站住！ ‪-抓住他们！
-Royal Tutor Jung. -Let me pass. I must go.
‪-郑司书 ‪-请让开 我得追上去
-They already got away. -I have to find out something.
‪-他们已经逃走了 ‪-我有事得查清楚
Why are you so reckless?
‪你为何如此莽撞？
The cut is deep.
‪伤口很深
We should get this treated first.
‪得先治疗才行
I'm okay. Are you all right, Your Royal Highness?
‪我没事 您还好吗？邸下
You have another cut?
‪这里也受伤了吗？
And here too?
‪这里也是？
Where else? Are there any more wounds?
‪你还伤到了哪里？
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
Why on earth did you do this?
‪你到底为何要做这种事？
You can lean on me.
‪我扶你
-Pardon? -How can you walk with those injured legs?
‪-什么？ ‪-你的腿伤成这样还能走吗？
You can lean on me to walk.
‪所以我扶着你走
Be careful.
‪小心
What brings you here in the middle of the night?
‪你怎么会在大半夜来这种地方呢？
I wanted to visit a few places as I haven't been in my hometown for so long.
‪我暌违已久回到故乡 ‪想到几个地方走走
-Is there anything wrong with that? -I see.
‪-这有什么不对吗？ ‪-这样啊
Interestingly enough, we received a report about suspicious movement around there.
‪不过偏偏有人回报在那附近 ‪发现了不寻常的动静
I was concerned that you might be the target of an assassin.
‪我担心那是要狙击你的刺客
As I'm in charge of the reception, I couldn't stop worrying about you.
‪作为接待使臣的负责人 ‪不得不操这个心啊
But you have nothing to worry about. Call off your men.
‪你白担心了 请撤退官兵吧
I can't do that.
‪万万不可啊
I must make sure that there won't be any more incidents.
‪为避免滋生任何事端
So until the day you leave Joseon,
‪在太监离开朝鲜前
security at this guesthouse will be strengthened.
‪会再加强太平馆的护卫
I'm sure his secret ledger must be somewhere around his quarters.
‪太监的秘密账簿 ‪肯定是藏在他的住所周围
Watch his every movement.
‪密切关注他的所有动向
Yes, my lord.
‪是 大监
I heard that the Chief Eunuch met with a suspicious man.
‪我听说太监跟可疑人物碰面
So I was tailing him.
‪便尾随在他身后
The Chief Eunuch?
‪太监吗？
But still. This was reckless.
‪但你也不能如此莽撞啊
I'm sorry, Your Royal Highness.
‪臣惶恐
I wanted to be of help.
‪臣希望能助您一臂之力
Do the wounds still hurt?
‪伤口还在隐隐作痛吗？
No.
‪现在不痛了
By the way,
‪不过
were you that worried about me?
‪原来您这么担心我啊？
I understand. If something happens to me,
‪也是啦 万一我有什么不测
you won't be able to find a good replacement to take my position.
‪您就找不到像我这么优秀的司书了
I get why you were concerned.
‪难怪您会担忧害怕
How can you joke right now?
‪你现在还笑得出来啊？
Your Royal Highness. I'm really hurt.
‪邸下 我的伤口真的很痛
Royal Tutor Jung. Are you all right?
‪郑司书 你没事吧？
Sorry.
‪对不起
Let's go.
‪快走吧
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
Are you all right? Why are you…
‪您没事吧？您怎么会…
Hyun, I can't believe you.
‪你太过分了 王兄
You didn't even tell me.
‪都没告知我一声
Well…
‪那是因为…
I…
‪那个…
So what is your plan now?
‪所以你现在有何打算？
Let me join you. I would like to be a part of this.
‪一起行动吧 也让我加入
Why are you looking for this man?
‪你为何要找此人？
Well, I like to collect rare objects.
‪我乐于搜集稀世珍宝
And I hear that his collection is very extensive.
‪四处都在流传他手上握有许多好东西
I will pay you handsomely for the introduction.
‪我会给你丰厚的介绍费
It's a very handsome sum of money, indeed.
‪相当丰厚的一笔
He already left the items with me.
‪他已经把东西卖给我了
Then we'd like to buy them too.
‪那我们也会把那个买下来
I'll double the price.
‪我出双倍的价格
Well, this is quite a large sum you're talking about. How…
‪那可不是笔小数目 两位意下如何？
As you can see, we're nothing without our good looks
‪如你所见 我们除了俊俏的外貌
and wealth.
‪和雄厚的财力之外就一无所有了
Here.
‪在这里
He became quite a gambling addict.
‪他可是个赌鬼啊
He was arrogant because his daughter became an imperial concubine in Ming.
‪仗着自己的女儿是明国的嫔妃 ‪就趾高气扬的
So I definitely remember his face.
‪他的长相我记得一清二楚
My goodness. This is quite a rarity.
‪唉唷 这种稀世珍宝
I hear the Emperor adores your daughter. I guess what I heard was true.
‪听说令嫒深受皇帝陛下的宠爱
But you didn't believe me before.
‪你之前还抵死不信
Just get me a good price for that. Okay?
‪给我个好价钱吧
He got a large sum for the items the Chief Eunuch gave him.
‪他卖掉太监给他的物品 ‪势必能拿到一笔可观的收入
So he'll check this place out first.
‪他肯定会先去这里报到
-Are you serious? -Come on.
‪-真的吗？ ‪-来啊
If we catch the imperial concubine's father,
‪抓到那个嫔妃之父
we'll be able to find out why he threatened the Chief Eunuch.
‪就能得知他拿什么威胁太监了
And that will be the Chief Eunuch's weakness.
‪那就会成为太监的把柄
Come on.
‪真是的
My goodness. I feel awful about taking all this money.
‪唉唷 真是不好意思啊
It looks like I won this round, brother.
‪这一局是我赢了 大哥
Come on! You're ruining my day.
‪唉唷 真是倒霉
Hold on. Are you leaving?
‪等等 你要走了？
Can't you see that I lost all of my money?
‪你没看到我全输光了吗？
Come on. I thought you knew better.
‪真是的 你明明是内行人 ‪怎么还这样？
If you leave now, we won't be able to play anymore. Right?
‪少了一个人 今天就玩不下去了
Exactly.
‪就是啊
Come on. Sit down. I'll lend you some money.
‪坐下吧 我借筹码给你
I'm not a heartless person, you know?
‪我可不是那么无情的人
What? This is…
‪等等 这个…
What? Do you know what it is?
‪怎么？你认得这支发簪？
It's really rare.
‪那真的很珍贵
That's from Ming.
‪可是从明国带过来的
Of course, I know.
‪我当然很清楚
I sold this.
‪这是我卖掉的
Goodness. I guess we were meant to cross paths.
‪天啊 看来我们真的很有缘呢
I've been looking everywhere for you!
‪我可是四处在找你啊 大哥
The soldiers are here!
‪官兵来了！
-The soldiers are here! -The soldiers?
‪-官兵来了 ‪-大哥
That way!
‪往那边
I'm so sorry, my lord! Please forgive me.
‪大人！小的知错了 请饶命啊
I was trying to make money to buy medicine for my sister.
‪小的只是来赚取妹妹的药材费
What? Who are you?
‪怎么回事？臭小子 你是什么人？
Well, that's none of your business.
‪这你不用知道
I need you to come with me.
‪要劳烦你跟我走一趟
Don't come close.
‪不准过来 别靠近我
Just drop the dagger. You'll just end up getting hurt.
‪把刀放下 你那样只会伤到你自己
Hey, my arm hurts. You're going to break my arm.
‪我的手很痛 好像快被折断了
Goodness. This isn't even a tight hold. Stop exaggerating.
‪真是的 我根本还没出力 你就在哀号
How about now? Is that better?
‪怎么样？这样行了吧？
Damn it.
‪该死
-Don't follow me. -Come on. We can talk it out.
‪-别过来 ‪-我们好好谈一下
Seriously. We can talk about it.
‪大哥 我们好好谈嘛 可恶
Come on, hurry. Go get him!
‪嘿 赶紧来啊 把他带过来！
Go!
‪走！
Take him with you. I'll handle them.
‪你把他带走吧 这边交给我解决
Are you sure?
‪你可以吗？
Of course.
‪那还用说
Go straight there. Don't lose him.
‪直接赶回去 人不要被劫走了
Wait. No.
‪等等 不是 我…
Hey!
‪喂
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
Can you handle them alone?
‪你一个人应付得了吗？
Of course, Your Royal Highness.
‪当然没问题 邸下
Sorry, we're late.
‪我们来晚了
No, you are right on time.
‪你们来得正好
Had you been a moment late, I wouldn't have been all right.
‪再晚一步 我可能就撑不住了
-Get on the horse. -Yes, Your Royal Highness.
‪-快上马 ‪-是
I appreciate it.
‪拜托你了
You never listen.
‪你真是不听话
I told you not to get hurt.
‪都吩咐你绝不能受伤了
I'm sorry.
‪臣惶恐
You sure make it sound painful when the wound is minor.
‪明明就是小伤还爱装疼
What? That's not true.
‪什么？我哪有装疼？
You saw my wound.
‪您没看到这个伤口吗？
It hurt a lot.
‪这有多痛啊
Others would have made a fuss about it.
‪是我才能这样忍下来
Thank you…
‪谢谢你
for enduring the pain.
‪忍住疼痛
And…
‪还有
for helping me.
‪与我并肩同行
I would like to continue to do so by your side.
‪臣日后也想一直陪在您身边
That is only if you will allow it, Your Royal Highness.
‪只要您同意的话
Please spare me.
‪求求您饶了小的一命
All right. Tell me.
‪好 现在从实招来
What is it that the Chief Eunuch is hiding?
‪太监隐瞒的究竟是什么
Well…
‪那个…
What's all this?
‪这些是什么？
Why the long face?
‪你为何板着一张脸？
Please take a seat.
‪请坐
We could have easily resolved the matter over drinks.
‪男人之间能借着酒席 ‪坦诚以对 化解间隙
Perhaps, I was too rigid.
‪之前是我太不识趣了
As a peace offering,
‪作为和解
I would like to show you
‪我也想让你瞧瞧
something interesting as well.
‪一个有趣的东西
You are indeed audacious
‪你的胆子还真大
to have coveted the Emperor's wealth.
‪竟敢觊觎皇帝的财物
Records of your management of the Emperor's private assets
‪这是你管理皇帝内帑金的记录
How did you get that?
‪那怎么会在你手上？
We will not be able to comply with your tribute request.
‪你要求的贡品我们无法应允
And if the Emperor were to find out, you would be in a tight spot too.
‪一旦皇帝得知此事
Wouldn't you?
‪你说是不是啊？
Is this why you wanted
‪您找我过来
to see me?
‪就为了此事吗？
Why?
‪怎么了？
I guess there are more secrets that you're hiding besides this one.
‪看来你还有其他秘密怕被人发现啊
I will keep this safe.
‪这我会妥善保管
You worked hard to build your reputation away from home.
‪你在异乡好不容易累积起来的名声
So it would be a shame to destroy it so easily like this.
‪可不能如此虚无地毁于一旦啊
So you told the Crown Prince everything.
‪你把一切都如实告诉世子了
He was going to kill me otherwise.
‪眼看小命都要不保了 ‪我还有什么办法？
What should we do now?
‪现在该怎么做比较好？
If your relationship with her is revealed,
‪你跟静的关系曝光的话
it will be the end for all of us.
‪我们全都会完蛋吧？
Please help my daughter. Take pity on her and protect her. Please?
‪求求你救救我 ‪那可怜的女儿 好不好？
You threatened me with her life before.
‪你之前还拿她的性命来要胁我
Now, you're worried?
‪现在会担心了是吧？
Goodness.
‪天啊
I told him to leave quietly.
‪我要他安静地离开
But he must have gone to see you.
‪结果他偏要去找你
What are you plotting?
‪你到底在打什么算盘？
You found something bigger than the book. Why pretend you didn't?
‪为何抓住更大的把柄 ‪却还佯装不知 加以隐瞒？
I didn't pretend anything.
‪我从未隐瞒
I didn't need to use your heartbreaking love story.
‪反正不提你那凄美的爱情故事
I already had the ledger that proved that you stole from the Emperor.
‪我手中也已握有你盗用内帑金的账簿
I just wasn't interested in your story.
‪我只是对那种情爱纠葛毫无兴趣罢了
Right.
‪对了
I must say I was a bit surprised.
‪我有些讶异
Not only did the father of a concubine sell off his own daughter,
‪他不但将自己的女儿卖去当嫔妃
but he also bargained over her life while threatening to expose you for money.
‪甚至还以你们的关系作为要胁 ‪用她的命向你索取封口费
Despite that, you were able to put up with him.
‪你却任由他狮子大开口
Is that how much you love her?
‪这表示你是如此地深爱她吗？
A concubine of the Emperor?
‪爱着那个皇帝的嫔妃
Don't you dare talk about her.
‪不准你用那张臭嘴提起她
If you ever go after her,
‪你要是敢动她分毫
I will make you pay for it!
‪我绝不会放过你！
I will use everything I have
‪我会动用我拥有的一切
to take revenge on you and Joseon!
‪来向你和朝鲜复仇！
Revenge?
‪复仇？
I heard that your parents received
‪我听说你父母卖掉你而换来的
a mere bag of rice when they sold you off.
‪不过是一石大米而已
By the time you crossed the border, your feet had blisters and were chapped.
‪你赤着脚不断走着 ‪走到磨破了皮 最后越过国境
But because you were a foreigner,
‪想必又碍于异乡人的身份
you were probably beaten up.
‪而饱受欺凌
And you probably spent every single night of your entire life,
‪你可能夜夜 ‪都在埋怨着卖掉你的父母
resenting your parents for selling you off
‪与放任无辜百姓被带至他国的朝鲜
and resenting Joseon for giving away innocent people.
‪借此活下去
I get why you wanted to take revenge.
‪怪不得你会想复仇
And you must have been disgusted to see people trying to flatter you
‪现在你看到对你唯唯诺诺的人
after what you achieved.
‪想必感到十分作呕吧
However,
‪但是
you shouldn't have behaved that way.
‪就因为如此 你更不该那么做
I doubt you went through all that trouble, so you could be like one of them.
‪你并不是想跟他们同流合污 ‪才千辛万苦爬到今天的地位
Get off your high horse.
‪少自命清高了
To me,
‪你对我而言
you are just like them.
‪跟他们没什么两样 全是一丘之貉
You are right.
‪对 没错
I am no different from them.
‪我也跟他们没什么两样
No.
‪不
You must resent me even more as I'm the Crown Prince of Joseon
‪朝鲜抛弃了你 我却身为朝鲜的世子
that gave you away.
‪更让你恨之入骨吧
Shut your mouth.
‪住口
I don't need your pity.
‪我不想再听你那些同情我的话
This isn't pity.
‪这不是同情
I just wanted…
‪我只是
to apologize to you
‪想以朝鲜世子的身份
as the Crown Prince of Joseon.
‪向你道歉罢了
A long time ago,
‪那时
you were forced to leave without proper clothes or food.
‪你饥寒交迫地离开这个国家
I apologize.
‪我想请求你的原谅
I will take your secret affair to my grave as well.
‪你跟她的秘密 我也会深埋心底
You two must have gone through a lot of pain to protect your love.
‪你们为了守护这份感情
I think…
‪我也…
I can somewhat relate to that.
‪稍稍能够体会
Feeling wronged?
‪冤枉吗？
-Don't look at me like that. -You stole it, didn't you?
‪-别用这种眼神看我 ‪-你偷了吧？
Answer me. If you don't, I'll have you killed.
‪说 不说就把你拉过去杀了
Get lost. Just go back to your homeland.
‪滚 就回国家去吧
Bastard.
‪死小子
Are you all right?
‪你还好吗？
It hurts a lot, right?
‪很痛吧？
Look at all this blood.
‪流了好多血
You don't know…
‪不知道
when you'll be back here.
‪你什么时候会再来
You should look around a bit more before going back.
‪请再多看看吧
After all, this is your homeland.
‪这可是您的故土啊
Homeland, my foot.
‪什么故土啊？
I am indebted to both of you.
‪承蒙两位相助之恩
You too. You were very helpful too.
‪你也辛苦了
Come and have a drink with us tonight.
‪今天就跟我们一起喝一杯吧
Sit comfortably.
‪随意坐吧
All right. Everyone, if you have a drink,
‪来 大家都把酒斟满
let's clink our glasses. What do you say, Your Royal Highness?
‪一起干一杯吧 邸下
Cheers.
‪干杯
Since when did you become so loyal to His Royal Highness?
‪你何时变成邸下的忠臣了啊？
You of all people.
‪我们的郑司书
Well,
‪那个嘛
you know that I'm nothing without my loyalty.
‪邸下 您知道我这个人最有义气了
Right, Your Royal Highness?
‪您说是不是？
Sure.
‪这个嘛
Yes. I guess so.
‪对 应该是吧
Your Royal Highness, are you serious?
‪邸下 您真的要这样对我吗？
You're really hurting my feelings.
‪我真的很伤心
I get it. Calm down. I just have something to tell him.
‪我知道了 你先冷静下来 ‪我有话要跟邸下…
Come on. I must talk to His Royal Highness.
‪我有话要跟邸下说！
Your Royal Highness. How can you laugh now?
‪邸下 您为何在笑？
Your Royal Highness, I cannot let this slide.
‪邸下 我这次一定要追究到底
You are hurting my feelings right now.
‪您那样说 可会让我伤心啊
Why don't you just sit down?
‪快坐下
Come on, Lord Jaeun. Help me out. Did you mean that, Your Royal Highness?
‪君大监 您帮帮我啊
All right.
‪好
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
Why don't we have just one more drink?
‪再喝一杯就好
Just one more.
‪再一杯就好
Come on, move.
‪你让开
I'm asking if he wants to have one more drink.
‪我在邀邸下再喝一杯
Let's have one more drink.
‪邸下 再喝一杯吧
Gosh.
‪真是的
Can you escort Royal Tutor Jung?
‪你送郑司书回去
I'll escort the Crown Prince.
‪邸下由我来护驾
Lord Jaeun. I'm not drunk.
‪君大监 我没有醉
Lord Jaeun. Your Royal Highness. Wait.
‪君大监！邸下 唉唷 邸下 等一下
Can't we have one more drink? Just one, please?
‪邸下 我们不能再喝一杯吗？
My arm hurts. Can you hold on a moment?
‪唉唷 我的手 等一下
Wait. Please wait.
‪等一下 你放开我
Hold on. My arm hurts.
‪放开我 我的手好痛
Listen. Hey.
‪我说你 喂
I'm not drunk.
‪我没有醉
I told you I'm not drunk. Why are you so…
‪都说我没醉了
Come on. Talk to me.
‪我们谈一谈 谈一下…
Gosh.
‪唉唷
Just one drink. Please?
‪再一杯就好 好吗？
Do you want to have one more drink with me?
‪我们俩再喝一杯如何？
I always felt that there was a brotherly bond between us.
‪我从以前就把你当成弟弟看待了
You felt it too. Right?
‪你也是这样对吧？
Not really.
‪我没有
Gosh. What a heartless man.
‪可恶 真是个无情的人
I have to talk to him. Gosh.
‪我有事要禀报 唉唷
Come on.
‪真是的
Why can't I stop smiling?
‪怎么止不住笑意？
I can't stop smiling?
‪止不住？
Why? Why can't I stop…
‪为何我会止不住…
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
Royal Tutor Jung.
‪郑司书
What are you doing here all alone?
‪你一个人待在这里做什么？
Well…
‪那个…
I was surprised.
‪我很讶异
That girl and I are the only ones who know about this place.
‪知道这个地方的 ‪只有我跟那个女孩而已
I saw fireflies and followed them.
‪因为萤火虫很亮 我一路尾随它们
And I stumbled upon this place by chance.
‪才偶然发现这里
The door… I found the door.
‪我发现那里有道门
Did you set this place up by yourself?
‪这全是你布置的吗？
This? Yes.
‪这些啊？对
That's why you had the flowers at the tavern.
‪所以你才会抱着那些花去酒馆啊
But…
‪不过
why do you have so much liquor here?
‪这些酒是怎么回事？
Well…
‪这些啊…
I couldn't sleep.
‪我睡不着
And everyone said no to more drinks.
‪而且大家都这么无情
I was just getting started, you know.
‪我才正要开喝呢
Is that why
‪所以
you are using the palace as your private tavern?
‪你就把宫里当成你私人的酒馆吗？
Only sometimes…
‪也没有啦 就只是偶尔…
I am. I can't deny that.
‪是 臣无法否认
That is typical of you.
‪真像你的作风
Please don't smile like that.
‪您不要那样笑
-What? -Pardon?
‪-什么？
I mean… Well, I meant to say…
‪不是…
Right. I wanted to ask you a question.
‪对了 臣有事想问您
Did you not expose the Chief Eunuch
‪您真的把那女子
because you really believe the imperial concubine lives
‪当成是太监生活的意义
for the Chief Eunuch?
‪就这样放他走吗？
Their lives were determined by other people's decisions.
‪他们无法选择自己想要的生活
So they had to hide their love.
‪所以只能隐藏他们的情感
And that broke my heart.
‪实在让我很心疼
You intrigue me sometimes.
‪您偶尔会让我感到很神奇
When I first met you at the courtesan house,
‪我们初次在妓院见面时
you were as cold as ice.
‪您明明是一副冷若冰霜的样子
But deep down, you seem to be tenderhearted.
‪实际上却如此心软
You should slow down.
‪你喝慢一点
You already drank a lot earlier.
‪你方才也喝了很多
Well, I was thirsty.
‪因为我有点口渴
Someone I know got drunk
‪我的一个熟人
and kissed the cheek of the person next to him.
‪喝醉后亲了身边的人的脸颊
Does he like that person?
‪他喜欢那个人吗？
Sometimes, you see and hear things.
‪有时候会出现幻觉和幻听
You're lovesick!
‪那是相思病啊！
No! That can't be.
‪不是的！
I deserve to die, Your Royal Highness.
‪臣罪该万死 邸下
You seem to be from a noble family. Why are you here in the palace alone?
‪你似乎出身于两班世家 ‪为何独自在宫中游走？
The selection of a princess?
‪拣择？
We must hold a royal marriage, so he can produce an heir.
‪得尽快举行国婚 才能孕育后代
The Crown Prince is getting married?
‪邸下要成亲了吗？
Have you ever loved someone, Your Royal Highness?
‪你没有心上人吗？邸下
I have a favor to ask, Your Royal Highness.
‪臣有个请求 邸下
Please give me a hug.
‪请给我一个拥抱
Subtitle translation by: Won-hyang Son
‪字幕翻译：钟见悦